Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject Files, 1893-1967; Series II; 24.5 linear feet (59 boxes)
  - Anthropoid Research
    - Sites for Station: miscellaneous information, 1926-1928 (Box 58, Folder 1102)
    - Bermuda as site for station, 1926-1929 (Box 58, Folder 1103)
    - Gorilla Congo, 1925-1928 (Box 58, Folder 1104)
    - Gorilla Congo: clippings, 1927-1930 (Box 58, Folder 1105)
    - Gorilla Bambo, 1927-1930 (Box 58, Folder 1106)
    - Columbia Expedition to Africa for gorillas, 1929 (Box 58, Folder 1107)
    - Physiography of Belgian Congo, 1929 (Box 58, Folder 1108)
    - Yale-Carnegie African expedition, 1929-1930 (Box 58, Folder 1109-1110)
    - George F. Getz, 1930-1931 (Box 58, Folder 1111)
    - George F. Getz, 1932-1934 (Box 59, Folder 1112)
    - Proposed Pan Paniscus Expedition, 1934-1938 (Box 59, Folder 1113)
    - Publicity re: Gorilla Congo and anthropoid work, 1916-1933 (Box 59, Folder 1114-1115)
  - Book Dealers
    - Fiedler, Henry George, 1929-1933 (Box 59, Folder 1116)
    - Fock, Gustave, 1932 (Box 59, Folder 1117)
    - Harassowitz, Otto, 1923-1927 (Box 59, Folder 1118)
    - Heffer & Sons, 1923-1931 (Box 59, Folder 1119)
    - Junk, W., 1929-1937 (Box 59, Folder 1120)
    - Login & Sons, 1925-1932 (Box 59, Folder 1121)
    - Stechert, G.E. & Co., 1910-1947 (Box 59, Folder 1122)
    - Whitlocks, 1932-1944 (Box 59, Folder 1123)
    - Miscellaneous, 1923-1948 (Box 59, Folder 1124-1125)
  - Causes
    - Eugenics, 1912-1916 (Box 59, Folder 1126-1129)
      See also: box 60, folder 1138 box 80, folders 1519-1520 box 80, folder 1545
    - Openmindedness; materials on projects for developing tolerance, 1943-1944 (Box 59, Folder 1130)
    - Universal Registration, 1932-1944 (Box 59, Folder 1131)
    - Political correspondence and miscellaneous causes, 1909-1953 (Box 59, Folder 1132-1133)
  - Chimpanzees
    - Clippings: on RMY and laboratory apes, 1914-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1134-1135)
    - Strassburg's educated apes, 1937-1944 (Box 60, Folder 1136)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1137)
  - Committees
    - American Breeders' Association, Committee on Psychic Heredity, 1911-1914 (Box 60, Folder 1138)
    - American Social Hygiene Association, Social Hygiene Committee of Yale, 1924-1928 (Box 60, Folder 1139-1140)
    - Bureau of Social Hygiene, Committee on Drug Addictions, 1925-1928 (Box 60, Folder 1141)
    - Carnegie Institute of Washington, Advisory Committee on Research on Human Behavior, 1921-1933 (Box 60, Folder 1142-1144)
    - Eugenics Research Association, Committee on Study of Human Behavior, 1925-1926 (Box 60, Folder 1145)
    - National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor, 1915-1922 (Box 60, Folder 1146)
    - Committee of 100 on Scientific Research, 1925 (Box 60, Folder 1147)
    - Committee on Psychological Abstracts, 1923-1926 (Box 60, Folder 1148)
    - Committee of Psychologists to Advise College Entrance Examination Board on Psychological Tests, 1925 (Box 60, Folder 1149)
    - President's Committee of Fifty on College Hygiene, 1922-1927 (Box 60, Folder 1150)
    - Rockland State Hospital, Scientific Advisory Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 60, Folder 1151)
  - Conferences
    - Conference on Experimental Neurosis, 1937 (Box 61, Folder 1152)
    - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1930-1931 (Box 61, Folder 1153)
    - Conference on Individual Psychological Differences, 1930 (Box 61, Folder 1154)
    - Hanover Conference, 1925-1927 (Box 61, Folder 1155-1157)
  - Congresses
    - 6th to 10th International Congresses of Psychology, 1908-1932 (Box 61, Folder 1158-1160)
    - 2nd and 3rd International Congresses of Eugenics, 1932 (Box 61, Folder 1161)
    - 1st International Congress on Mental Hygiene, 1929-1930 (Box 61, Folder 1162)
    - 6th International Congress of Genetics, 1932 (Box 61, Folder 1163)
  - Editor: Harvard Psychological Studies, [1902] (Box 61, Folder 1164)
  - Editor of Journals and Series
    - (Animal) Behavior Monographs, 1921-1954 (Box 61, Folder 1165-1166)
    - Animal Behavior Series, 1907 (Box 61, Folder 1167)
    - Animal Behavior Series, 1907-1917 (Box 62, Folder 1168-1170)
    - Journal of Animal Behavior, 1910-1941 (Box 62, Folder 1171)
    - Journal of Comparative Neurology and Psychology, 1904-1910 (Box 62, Folder 1172)
    - Journal of Comparative Psychology, 1921-1943 (Box 62, Folder 1173-1183)
    - Comparative Psychology Monographs, 1922-1926 (Box 62, Folder 1184)
    - Comparative Psychology Monographs, 1927-1946 (Box 63, Folder 1185-1187)
  - Experiment Stations
    - Biological Station of I.P. Pavlov, 1934, 1936 (Box 63, Folder 1188)
    - Institute for Research in Tropical America, Barro Colorado Island, Panama Canal, 1931-1940 (Box 63, Folder 1189-1190)
    - Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1934 (Box 63, Folder 1191)
    - School of Tropical Medicine, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1937-1942 (Box 63, Folder 1192-1194)
    - Suchum, Caucasus, USSR, 1929-1935 (Box 63, Folder 1195)
  - Fellowships
    - Guggenheim rules, 1925-1941 (Box 63, Folder 1196)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1926-1950 (Box 63, Folder 1197)
    - Sterling Fellowships, undated (Box 63, Folder 1198)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1940, undated (Box 63, Folder 1199)
  - Fels (Samuel S.) Fund
    - Infant Studies Program, 1939-1951 (Box 63, Folder 1200)
    - Frederick P. Gruenberg, Organization of Science Advisory Committee for Research in Child Development, 1944-1952 (Box 63, Folder 1201-1204)
    - Frederick P. Gruenberg (continuation), 1953-1956 (Box 64, Folder 1205)
  - Fels (Samuel S.) Research Institute
    - Appraisal of Fels Institute by RMY, 1944-1945 (Box 64, Folder 1206-1207)
    - Scientific Advisory Committee, 1944-1950 (Box 64, Folder 1208-1212)
    - Lester W. Sontag, 1942-1955 (Box 64, Folder 1213-1218)
    - Dedication of new laboratories of the Fels Research Institute, 1947 (Box 64, Folder 1219)
    - Annual reports, 1951, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 1220)
    - Antioch College correspondence, 1944-1955 (Box 65, Folder 1221)
  - George, Wesley C., 1962-1966 (Box 65, Folder 1222)
  - Gorillas
    - Gorilla bibliography, 1928 (Box 65, Folder 1223)
    - Outline and classification of subjects, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1224)
    - San Diego Zoo notes, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1225)
    - notes, 1950-1951 (Box 65, Folder 1226-1228)
    - Test Apparatus for young gorillas, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1229)
    - "Purring" and other notes, 1950-1951 (Box 65, Folder 1230)
      See also: box 178, folder 2691
    - "Gorilla Census and Study", 1951 (Box 65, Folder 1231)
    - Material for revised "Census", 1952-1953 (Box 65, Folder 1232)
    - Gorilla census (Philadelphia zoo), 1960 (Box 65, Folder 1233)
    - General gorilla correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 65, Folder 1234)
    - Footage in film Mogambo, 1952-1954 (Box 66, Folder 1235)
    - Photographs, 1944-1952 (Box 66, Folder 1236)
    - Clippings, 1950-1956 (Box 66, Folder 1237-1238)
  - Gorilla Studies
    - Arundel, Arthur W., 1955 (Box 66, Folder 1239)
    - Rean, Robert: Brookfield Zoo, Chicago, 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 1240)
    - Benchley, Belle J., 1949-1957 (Box 66, Folder 1241-1246)
    - Buck, Warren E., 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 1247)
    - Carpenter, Clarence Ray, 1950 (Box 66, Folder 1248)
    - Current Research, Manuscript by Yerkes and Benchley, 1950 (Box 66, Folder 1249)
    - Davis, Earl F.: Columbus Zoological Society, 1950 (Box 66, Folder 1250)
    - Denis, Armand: Anthropoid Research Foundation, Inc., 1951 (Box 66, Folder 1251)
    - DuMond, Joseph: (Mookey Jungle) Goulds, Florida, 1951 (Box 66, Folder 1252)
    - Elder, James H., 1950 (Box 66, Folder 1253)
    - Fulton, John F., 1951-1954 (Box 66, Folder 1254)
    - Galm, John: Central Park Zoo, 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1255)
    - Greer, C.B., 1952-1954 (Box 67, Folder 1256)
    - Gromier, E., 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1257)
    - Harlow, Harry, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 1258)
    - Harwell, Edalee Orcutt: Zoological Society of San Diego, 1950-1953 (Box 67, Folder 1259-1262)
    - Heuseer, J.F.: Cincinnati Zoological Society, 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1263)
    - Hunter, Martha G., 1950-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1264-1265)
    - Journal of Mammalogy, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 1266)
    - Kelly, Arthur L., 1950 (Box 67, Folder 1267)
    - Kelly, Joan Morton, 1950-1957 (Box 67, Folder 1268)
    - Leary, Robert W., 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1269)
    - Lintz, Gertrude D., 1951 (Box 67, Folder 1270)
    - Lowman, Mrs. R.B., 1952-1954 (Box 67, Folder 1271)
    - Menary, Robert V.: Cheyenne Mountain Museum and Zoological Society, Colorado Springs, 1950-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1272)
    - New York Zoological Park, 1951-1953 (Box 67, Folder 1273)
    - Noell, Mrs. Robert: Robert Noell Animal Show, 1950-1951 (Box 67, Folder 1274-1277)
    - North, John and Henry Ringling North: Ringling Brothers Circus, 1948-1954 (Box 67, Folder 1278)
    - Perkins, R. Marlin: Lincoln Park Zoological Gardens, Chicago, 1950-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1279)
    - Reynolds, Fletcher A.: Cleveland Zoological Park, 1950-1952 (Box 67, Folder 1280)
    - Riesen, Austin H., 1950 (Box 67, Folder 1281)
    - Said, William, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 1282)
    - Schroeder. C.R.: San Diego Zoo, 1953-1954 (Box 68, Folder 1283)
    - Shelly, Freeman M.: Philadelphia Zoological Garden, 1950-1952 (Box 68, Folder 1284)
    - Sparks, Richard D., 1950-1954 (Box 68, Folder 1285)
    - Speidel, George: Washington Park Zoological Gardens, Milwaukee, 1950-1955 (Box 68, Folder 1286)
    - Stark, Fred W.: San Antonio Zoological Society, 1951-1952 (Box 68, Folder 1287)
    - Stott, Ken Jr.: Zoological Society of San Diego, 1950-1954 (Box 68, Folder 1288)
    - Trefflich, Henry, 1950-1951 (Box 68, Folder 1289)
    - Vierheller, George P.; St. Louis Zoological Park, 1950-1952 (Box 68, Folder 1290)
    - Watson, Arthur R.: Baltimore Zoo, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 1291)
    - Way, Mary S., 1951-1953 (Box 68, Folder 1292)
  - Gorilla Survey: Emlen, John T., 1959-1964 (Box 68, Folder 1293)
  - Harvard University
    - Laboratory of Animal Psychology, 1899-1914 (Box 68, Folder 1294)
    - Committee to Visit the Psychology Department, 1945-1954 (Box 68, Folder 1295-1298)
    - Edwin B. Newman, 1948-1951 (Box 68, Folder 1299-1300)
    - Commission to Advise on the Future of Psychology at Harvard, 1945-1947 (Box 68, Folder 1301-1303)
    - Report of Commission to Advise on Future of Psychology at Harvard, 1946-1947 (Box 68, Folder 1304-1305)
    - Ad hoc Committee, 1946 (Box 68, Folder 1306)
    - "The Behavioral Sciences at Harvard", 1955 (Box 69, Folder 1307)
  - Institutions
    - American Museum of Natural History, 1924-1949 (Box 69, Folder 1308)
    - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1922-1934 (Box 69, Folder 1309)
    - Carnegie Institute of Washington, 1923-1941 (Box 69, Folder 1310)
    - Field Museum of Natural History, 1933 (Box 69, Folder 1311)
    - Markle (John and Mary R.) Foundation, 1939-1947 (Box 69, Folder 1312)
    - National Research Council, Division of Medical Sciences, 1939-1943 (Box 69, Folder 1313)
    - Pasteur Institute, Kindia, French Guinea, 1923-1936 (Box 69, Folder 1314-1316)
    - Peabody Museum of Archeology and Ethnology, Harvard University, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1317)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 1938-1946 (Box 69, Folder 1318)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1942 (Box 69, Folder 1319)
  - Intersociety Constitutional Convention
    - Continuation Committee, Chairman, Hilgard, 1943-1944 (Box 69, Folder 1320-1321)
    - Bryan, Alice I., secretary, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1322)
    - Joint Program, APA and AAAP, 1944 (Box 69, Folder 1323)
    - Handbook and agenda, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1324)
    - Convention material, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1325-1327)
    - American Chemical Society, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1328)
    - American Institute of Physics, 1943-1945 (Box 69, Folder 1329)
    - National Council of Women Psychologists, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 1330)
    - Other by-laws, 1942-1943 (Box 69, Folder 1331)
    - Other by-laws, 1942-1943 (Box 70, Folder 1332)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942-1943 (Box 70, Folder 1333)
  - Jackson (Roscoe B.) Memorial Laboratory
    - Conference on Genetic and Social Behavior, 1946 (Box 70, Folder 1334-1335)
    - Rebuilding after fire, 1947-1950 (Box 70, Folder 1336)
    - Committee for the Study of Animal Societies under Natural Conditions, 1947-1952 (Box 70, Folder 1337)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1919-1921 (Box 70, Folder 1338-1339)
  - Laboratory Animals
    - Supply of turtles, crabs, etc., 1900-1905 (Box 70, Folder 1340)
    - Cats, 1925-1934 (Box 70, Folder 1341)
    - Foods, 1925-1942 (Box 70, Folder 1342)
    - Monkeys, 1927-1929 (Box 70, Folder 1343)
    - Rats, 1921-1937 (Box 70, Folder 1344)
  - Minnesota, University of, 1916-1920 (Box 70, Folder 1345-1350)
    - Other, 1917-1923 (Box 70, Folder 1351)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Age tables, 1928 (Box 70, Folder 1352)
    - Bills, 1914-1941 (Box 71, Folder 1353)
    - Climate, undated (Box 71, Folder 1354)
    - Color terminology, 1922-1941 (Box 71, Folder 1355)
    - Inquiries, miscellaneous, 1936-1942 (Box 71, Folder 1356-1357)
    - Interviews, requests for, 1928-1932 (Box 71, Folder 1358)
    - Invitations to speak, 1915-1931 (Box 71, Folder 1359-1361)
    - Invitations, general, 1921-1941 (Box 71, Folder 1362)
    - "Psychobiology": origin and usage, 1934-1937 (Box 71, Folder 1363)
    - Psychobiological openings, 1925-1938 (Box 71, Folder 1364)
    - Requests for photographs, 1930-1941 (Box 71, Folder 1365)
    - Tropic Everglades Park, 1931 (Box 71, Folder 1366)
    - General, 1917-1954 (Box 71, Folder 1367)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1923-1943 (Box 71, Folder 1368-1371)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1944-1948 (Box 72, Folder 1372-1373)
    - Nominations, 1943-1955 (Box 72, Folder 1374-1382)
    - Committee on Albert National Park, 1925-1937 (Box 72, Folder 1383-1385)
    - Advisory Committee to Examine Armand Denis' Anthropoid Ape Research Foundation, Inc., 1945 (Box 72, Folder 1386)
    - National Science Fund, 1941-1942 (Box 72, Folder 1387)
  - National Research Council
    - Appointments to committees, 1917-1926 (Box 73, Folder 1388-1389)
    - Research Information Service, 1919-1924 (Box 73, Folder 1390-1392)
    - Division of Educational Relations, 1920-1921 (Box 73, Folder 1393)
    - Fellowships, 1928-1937 (Box 73, Folder 1394)
    - Division of Anthropology and Psychology, 1925-1947 (Box 73, Folder 1395-1396)
      - Committee on Classification of Military Personnel (Box 73, Folder 1397)
    - Committee on Scientific Problems of Human Migration
      - Diary of conferences, 1922-1923 (Box 73, Folder 1398)
      - Diary of conferences, 1923-1925 (Box 74, Folder 1399-1400)
      - Correspondence, reports, etc., 1923-1929 (Box 74, Folder 1401-1403)
    - Division of Anthropology and Psychology, Emergency Committee in Psychology
      - Appointment of, 1940-1941 (Box 74, Folder 1404)
      - Committees, problems, reports, 1941-1942 (Box 74, Folder 1405)
      - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 74, Folder 1406-1407)
      - Leonard Carmichael, 1942-1946 (Box 74, Folder 1408-1409)
      - Minutes, 1940-1942 (Box 74, Folder 1410-1414)
      - Minutes, 1942-1945 (Box 75, Folder 1415-1419)
      - Subcommittee on Survey and Planning for Psychology
        - Military Psychology Conference, 1944 (Box 75, Folder 1420-1421)
        - Report of Military Psychology Conference, 1944-1945 (Box 75, Folder 1422)
        - Subcommittee on Psychological Aspects of Readjustment, 1942-1943 (Box 75, Folder 1423)
        - Conferences in Philadelphia and Washington, 1942-1943 (Box 75, Folder 1424)
        - Committee for Army Specialist Training Program, 1942-1943 (Box 75, Folder 1425)
        - Subcommittee on Mental Deficiency, 1943-1944 (Box 75, Folder 1426)
        - Subcommittee on Coordination of Psychological Services, 1943-1945 (Box 75, Folder 1427)
        - Subcommittee on Textbook of Military Psychology, 1942 (Box 75, Folder 1428)
        - Subcommittee on Textbook of Military Psychology, 1943-1946 (Box 76, Folder 1429)
    - Division of Anthropology and Psychology
      - Committee on History of the National Research Council, 1944-1951 (Box 76, Folder 1430)
      - History of Psychology and the War, 1946 (Box 76, Folder 1431)
      - Committee on History of Psychology and the War, 1948 (Box 76, Folder 1432)
      - Miscellaneous minor matters, 1932-1954 (Box 76, Folder 1433)
      - National Roster of Scientific Personnel, 1942-1945 (Box 76, Folder 1434)
      - Office of Psychological Personnel
        - Creation of, 1941-1946 (Box 76, Folder 1435-1437)
        - Yerkes as consultant, 1942-1943 (Box 76, Folder 1438)
        - Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 76, Folder 1439-1440)
        - Donald Marquis, 1944 (Box 76, Folder 1441)
        - Registration, 1944-1945 (Box 76, Folder 1442)
    - Committee on Further Use of Army Data, 1919-1926 (Box 76, Folder 1443)
    - Committee on International Auxiliary Language, 1921 (Box 76, Folder 1444)
    - National Intelligence Tests, 1921 (Box 76, Folder 1445)
    - Committee on National Intelligence Tests, 1924-1942 (Box 76, Folder 1446-1447)
    - Committee on "Standard" Dogs, 1940 (Box 76, Folder 1448)
    - Committee on International Cooperation in Psychology, 1944-1954 (Box 76, Folder 1449-1451)
    - Division of Medical Sciences, 1946-1950 (Box 76, Folder 1452)
      - Agendas, 1946-1947 (Box 77, Folder 1453-1454)
      - Annual reports, 1946-1950 (Box 77, Folder 1455-1456)
    - Committee for Research in Problems of Sex
      - Regulations for investigators, 1922 (Box 77, Folder 1457)
      - Agenda for meeting of April 1948 (Box 77, Folder 1458)
      - Sockefeller Foundation, 1949-1953 (Box 77, Folder 1459-1460)
      - George W. Corner, chairman, 1947-1955 (Box 77, Folder 1461-1463)
      - Lois Bowen, 1952-1955 (Box 77, Folder 1464)
      - Congressional Committee on Tax Exempt Foundations, 1954 (Box 77, Folder 1465)
      - R.K. Cannan, 1954, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 1466)
      - Published reports of investigators, 1922-1930 (Box 77, Folder 1467)
      - Annual reports, 1922-1926 (Box 77, Folder 1468-1471)
      - Annual reports, 1926-1949 (Box 78, Folder 1472-1492)
      - Annual reports, 1950-1952 (Box 79, Folder 1493)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1921-1955 (Box 79, Folder 1494-1515)
  - Organizations
    - American Association of Scientific Workers, 1940 (Box 79, Folder 1516)
    - American Eugenics Society, 1923-1929 (Box 79, Folder 1517)
    - American Eugenics Society, 1930-1952 (Box 80, Folder 1518-1519)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1946-1947 (Box 80, Folder 1520)
    - American Legislators' Association, 1926-1933 (Box 80, Folder 1521)
    - American Russian Institute, 1945-1950 (Box 80, Folder 1522)
    - American-Russian Psychological Committee, 1936 (Box 80, Folder 1523)
    - American Social Hygiene Association, 1922-1950 (Box 80, Folder 1524-1526)
    - American Society of Mammologists, 1926-1947 (Box 80, Folder 1527)
    - American Society of Naturalists, 1927-1947 (Box 80, Folder 1528-1530)
    - American Society of Zoologists, 1917-1941 (Box 80, Folder 1531)
    - Boston Psychopathic Hospital, 1915-1916 (Box 80, Folder 1532)
    - Bureau of Public Personnel Administration, 1923-1924 (Box 80, Folder 1533)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1912-1922 (Box 80, Folder 1534-1536)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 1537)
    - Committee of One Hundred on National Health, 1913 (Box 80, Folder 1538)
    - Committee of One Thousand, 1948 (Box 80, Folder 1539)
    - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1932 (Box 80, Folder 1540)
    - Connecticut Merit System Association, 1936, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1541)
    - Connecticut Society of Psychologists, Committee on By-Laws, 1944-1947 (Box 80, Folder 1542-1543)
    - Connecticut State Psychological Society, 1947-1950 (Box 80, Folder 1544)
    - Eugenics Research Association, 1922-1931 (Box 80, Folder 1545)
    - Friends of Medical Progress, 1923 (Box 81, Folder 1546)
    - The Galton Society, 1919-1935 (Box 81, Folder 1547)
    - Illuminating Engineering Society, 1910-1913 (Box 81, Folder 1548-1549)
    - Institute of General Semantics, 1940-1942 (Box 81, Folder 1550)
    - International Labor Office, 1925-1928 (Box 81, Folder 1551)
    - Massachusetts Society for Mental Hygiene, 1912-1917 (Box 81, Folder 1552-1554)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1917-1940 (Box 81, Folder 1555-1559)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., 1945-1946 (Box 81, Folder 1560)
    - National Institute of Industrial Psychology, 1923-1925 (Box 81, Folder 1561)
    - National Institute of Psychology, 1929-1942 (Box 81, Folder 1562)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1935-1944 (Box 81, Folder 1563)
    - New York City Mental Hygiene Committee, Report on Selective Service, 1942 (Box 81, Folder 1564)
    - Pan-Pacific Union, 1924 (Box 81, Folder 1565)
    - Personnel Research Foundation, 1924-1929 (Box 81, Folder 1566)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1916-1947 (Box 81, Folder 1567)
    - Population Association of America, 1930-1947 (Box 82, Folder 1568-1571)
    - Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems, 1948 (Box 82, Folder 1572)
    - Société Française de Psychologie, 1930 (Box 82, Folder 1573)
    - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1936-1946 (Box 82, Folder 1574)
    - Sociometric Institute, 1942-1948 (Box 82, Folder 1575)
    - Washington Academy of Sciences, 1920-1925 (Box 82, Folder 1576)
    - World Court and League of Nations, 1923-1936 (Box 82, Folder 1577)
  - Periodicals
    - Acta Psychologica, 1933-1934 (Box 82, Folder 1578)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1914-1924 (Box 82, Folder 1579)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1926-1945 (Box 82, Folder 1580-1581)
    - Journal Press, 1937-1943 (Box 82, Folder 1582)
      - Antecedents, 1927-1937 (Box 82, Folder 1583)
    - Miscellaneous Journals, 1930-1948 (Box 82, Folder 1584-1586)
    - PM, 1946-1947 (Box 82, Folder 1587)
    - Proposed "Popular Science" Journal, 1919 (Box 82, Folder 1588)
    - Psychological Abstracts, 1928 (Box 82, Folder 1589)
    - Publication exchange, 1929-1937 (Box 82, Folder 1590)
    - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1925-1929 (Box 82, Folder 1591)
    - Science, 1945 (Box 82, Folder 1592)
    - Science Service, Inc., 1919-1931 (Box 82, Folder 1593-1596)
    - Science Service, Inc., 1932-1947 (Box 83, Folder 1597-1598)
    - Scientific American, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 1599)
  - Photographic
    - Bell and Howell, 1926-1937 (Box 83, Folder 1600)
    - Cinelab, Inc., 1927-1936 (Box 83, Folder 1601)
    - Edited films, 1925-1937 (Box 83, Folder 1602)
    - Fritz and Hawley, 1926-1940 (Box 83, Folder 1603)
    - Instructional films, 1925-1937 (Box 83, Folder 1604)
    - Motion pictures, 1929-1937 (Box 83, Folder 1605-1606)
    - "Ingagi" (fake film), 1930-1933 (Box 83, Folder 1607)
    - Phelpsfilms, Inc., 1931-1934 (Box 83, Folder 1608)
    - Photographers: general, 1941-1942 (Box 83, Folder 1609)
    - Photographic Division, Medical School, 1931-1941 (Box 83, Folder 1610)
    - Photographic equipment: general, 1927-1939 (Box 83, Folder 1611-1613)
    - Stoelting Co., 1935-1936 (Box 83, Folder 1614)
  - Psychological Corporation, 1920-1943 (Box 83, Folder 1615-1621)
  - Psychological Corporation, 1944-1953 (Box 84, Folder 1622-1625)
  - Publishers
    - Century Co., 1905-1925 (Box 84, Folder 1626)
    - Century Psychological Series, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 1627)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1945-1951 (Box 84, Folder 1628)
    - Henry Holt and Company, 1909-1937 (Box 84, Folder 1629-1631)
    - Macmillan and Appleton, 1904 (Box 84, Folder 1632)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1950 (Box 84, Folder 1633)
    - Stoelting, C.H. Co., 1910-1944 (Box 84, Folder 1634)
    - The Williams & Wilkins Company, 1920-1945 (Box 84, Folder 1635-1636)